<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>B1 Informatics 1 WS 2023/24 on STAGING DRAFTS --- Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/stagingdrafts/classes/ws2023/info1/</link><description>Recent content in B1 Informatics 1 WS 2023/24 on STAGING DRAFTS --- Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://bkleinen.github.io/stagingdrafts/classes/ws2023/info1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Code Examples</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/stagingdrafts/classes/ws2023/info1/code/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/stagingdrafts/classes/ws2023/info1/code/</guid><description>Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about noting down any code changes I make in class - I will upload everything to github!
If I make changes during class, I will push them to the branch with the semester name. To switch to the branch, select the according semester in the branches menu in the upper left corner on each repository&amp;rsquo;s main page.(it shows &amp;ldquo;main&amp;rdquo; usually - the default branch) Note that it might also be quite convenient to look at the code on the github page online, the commit history shows you the exact changes I made during class.</description></item><item><title>Info1 - Workbooks</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/stagingdrafts/classes/ws2023/info1/workbook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/stagingdrafts/classes/ws2023/info1/workbook/</guid><description>Workbook: Chapter Summaries and Exercises We encourage you to maintain hand-written notes and sketches. For this, we&amp;rsquo;ve prepared a workbook template (available in moodle) containing additional exercises and room for your notes. You can hand in your weekly notes for additional points .
We will provide Paper Worksheets for each Chapter in Moodle and encourage you to print them out and work on them with real pens.
Bind them to an A5 Workbook They will be provided in a format that allows you to bind them as a book later if you wish to.</description></item><item><title>Exercise 08: Bouncing Balls</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/stagingdrafts/classes/ws2023/info1/labs-archive/exercise-08/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/stagingdrafts/classes/ws2023/info1/labs-archive/exercise-08/</guid><description>This week&amp;rsquo;s lab work is intended give you practice working with the basic concepts of programming.
Pre Lab Prepare your prelab before coming to class! Doing the pre-lab will save you time during the lab.
P0. Download and open the Balls project (concerns Chapter 06 in the book). Create a BallDemo object and execute the drawDemo and bounce methods. Then read the BallDemo source code. Describe, in detail, how these methods work for your report.</description></item></channel></rss>