<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>B1 Informatics 1 SoSe 2022 on STAGING DRAFTS --- Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/stagingdrafts/classes/ss2022/info1/</link><description>Recent content in B1 Informatics 1 SoSe 2022 on STAGING DRAFTS --- Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://bkleinen.github.io/stagingdrafts/classes/ss2022/info1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Exercise 01: Programming Kara</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/stagingdrafts/classes/ss2022/info1/kara_ws2019/exercise-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/stagingdrafts/classes/ss2022/info1/kara_ws2019/exercise-01/</guid><description>Pre-Lab Download the Scenarios and read through the Kara programming exercises in the assignment.
Write down how Kara could solve the task for each one of them. For example, if the programming exercise was Exercise 4 from Worksheet 1, where Kara was to move in a Square and drop a leaf in each corner, you could write down something as this:
1. walk one edge (call move n times), 2.</description></item><item><title>Info 1 - Schedule</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/stagingdrafts/classes/ss2022/info1/schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/stagingdrafts/classes/ss2022/info1/schedule/</guid><description>1 Week KW Dates Lab Assignment Material 1 14 Thu 07/04/2022 Fri 08/04/2022 2 15 Thu 14/04/2022 Fri 15/04/2022 Ostern 3 16 Thu 21/04/2022 Introduction to Class &amp;amp; Labs, Chapter 01 - Objects and Classes Exercise 01 - Getting Started and Shapes Source Code, Fri 22/04/2022 Objects, Classes, Methods, BlueJ, Parameters, Compiler Video Part 1 , 2 4 17 Thu 28/04/2022 Chapter 02 - Understanding Class Definitions Exercise 02 - Ticket Machine Source Code Fri 29/04/2022 Class Definitions, Fields, Constructors, Methods, Parameters, Assignment, Getters and Setter, Printing to the command line, Conditional, Local Variables, Expressions Video Part 1 , 2 , 3 , 4 , 5 , 6 , 7 , 8 , 9 5 18 Thu 05/05/2022 Chapter 03 - Object Interaction Exercise 03 - Book Exercise Source Code Fri 06/05/2022 Abstraction, Modularization, Object Interaction, Object Creation, Object and Class Diagrams, Primitive Types, Object Types, Multiple Constructors, Debugger Video Part 1 , 2 6 19 Thu 12/05/2022 Chapter 04 - Grouping Objects Exercise 04 - Rock Around the Clock - Part 1 Source Code Fri 13/05/2022 Collections, Generics, for-each, While Loops, More Loops, Iterators, Arrays, For Loops Video Part 1 , 2 , 3 , 4 , 5 7 20 Thu 19/05/2022 Chapter 05 - Functional Processing of Collections (Advanced) Exercise 05 - Rock Around the Clock - Part 2 Source Code Fri 20/05/2022 Lambda Functions, Filter, Map, Reduce Video Part 1 , 2 21 Thu 26/05/2022 Himmelfahrt Vorlesungsfrei - Chapter 06 - More-Sophisticated Behavior Exercise 06 - A Better Notebook Source Code Fri 27/05/2022 Vorlesungsfrei Library Classes, Reading Class Documentation, Random, Packages, (Hash)Maps, Public vs.</description></item><item><title>Info1 - Code Examples Overview</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/stagingdrafts/classes/ss2022/info1/code/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/stagingdrafts/classes/ss2022/info1/code/</guid><description>Lecture Code Examples Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about noting down any code changes I make in class - I will upload everything to github! The &amp;ldquo;Changes in ss2021&amp;rdquo; links will only work after I&amp;rsquo;ve uploaded those changes.
Note that it might also be quite convenient to look at the code on the github page online, the commit history shows you the exact changes I made. Click on &amp;ldquo;commits&amp;rdquo; and then one individual commit, and you you&amp;rsquo;ll see the changes.</description></item><item><title>Info1 Notebooks</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/stagingdrafts/classes/ss2022/info1/notebook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/stagingdrafts/classes/ss2022/info1/notebook/</guid><description>Notebook: Chapter Summaries and Exercises We will provide Paper Worksheets for each Chapter and encourage you to print them out and work on them with real pens.
They will be provided in a format that allows you to bind them as a book later if you wish to.
See Frau Schimpf: DIY: Buchbinden – Offene Fadenheftung for an easy german instruction how this might be done, or How to Make a Sketchbook | DIY Coptic Stitch Bookbinding Tutorial | Sea Lemon for an english one which also shows a different way to attach the cover.</description></item><item><title>Lab Startup</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/stagingdrafts/classes/ss2022/info1/kara_ws2019/exercise-00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/stagingdrafts/classes/ss2022/info1/kara_ws2019/exercise-00/</guid><description>Welcome to the laboratory - that&amp;rsquo;s what we call these rooms filled with computer equipment. We have lots of rules for the labs, as they are used by many different people during the week. You find a link to the rules (&amp;ldquo;Laborordnung&amp;rdquo;) here.
Two really important rules are:
No food. We don&amp;rsquo;t like crumbs in the keyboards. Drinks are okay if they are in a container with a screw-on lid and the lid is screwed on.</description></item></channel></rss>